A Guide to the Business Archives of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1904-1979 (1914-1961)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Business Archives of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1904-1979 (1914-1961)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11582
The collection consists of 52 cubic boxes, ca. 65 linear feet. Approximate number of items: 58,000.
The records of this short line railroad based in Massie's Mill, Nelson County, Virginia, containing ca. 58,000 items, 1904-1979 (1914-1961), include its own extensive administrative, fiscal, and legal files, as well as those of the Bee Tree Lumber Company, the Hope Falls Timber Company, the Leftwich Timber Company, and the Tye River Timber Company. Also, considerable material concerning the operations of the Tidewater Lumber and Veneer Company in Honduras and British Honduras; the land promotion ventures of the Georgia Company, Georgia and the Great Western Land Company, Montana; and the titanium oxide and aplite industries along the railway line.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Shelved in remote storage. Users must request at least 24 hours in advance of desired use.
Acquisition Information
These papers were transferred to the University of Virginia Library by Cornell University Library on January 21, 2000.
Scope and Content
The Virginia Blue Ridge Railway covered about nineteen miles from Tye River to Massie's Mill, Nelson County, Virginia, the site of its principal office. The railroad was incorporated on May 22, 1914, and was originally built to haul chestnut timber for two timber companies, the Leftwich Timber Company and the Tye River Timber Company, who needed a common carrier railroad to connect the two lumber mills by rail with the Southern Railway near the village of Tye River. The track laying for the ten miles of the main line was completed in 1915, with the six mile spur into Massie's Mill becoming ready for use in October 1916. The carrier served the small towns of Massie's Mill, Lowesville, Woodson, Piney River, and Rose Mill.
The original corporate officers of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway when it was organized in 1914 were John W. Dwight (1859-1928), former U.S. Representative from New York, President; John W. Powell (?-1957) of Canisteo, New York, Vice-President and General Manager; Fordyce A. Cobb (?-1930), Secretary and Howard Cobb (?- [1948?]), Treasurer, both of Ithaca, New York; and Frank O. Lathrop, Superintendent.
The Tye River Timber Company owned the timber rights to the Cub Creek area timber, which it agreed to sell to the Bee Tree Lumber Company. This latter company was created to run the Massie's Mill timber operation and a bandsaw mill. The Tye River Timber Company was a holding company for the timber, with Howard Cobb as President and John W. Dwight as Secretary, and headquarters at Lynchburg. The Bee Tree Lumber Company was a West Virginia Corporation with offices at Blue Jay, West Virginia, with A.M. Kistler as President and H.N. Crowell as Secretary. The Bee Tree Lumber Company mill ceased operations in 1922, after the Cub Creek timber had been harvested.
The Leftwich Timber Company begun by R. Gilmore Leftwich (1875-1963), a Lynchburg businessman, was the second holding company created to secure timber rights and arrange with another company to build a mill to produce the lumber. The Leftwich Timber Company, with R.G. Leftwich as President and Howard Cobb as Secretary in 1913, owned timber rights to about 12,000 acres. By 1915 a modern bandsaw mill was under construction at Woodson, Virginia. During the early years, the actual management of the mill and wood operations was handled by A.J. White and Son Company.
When all railroads were nationalized during World War I, the two lumber mills were considered non-essential producers and the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway was shut down until after the Armistice was signed. The Woodson Mill resumed operations as the Woodson Lumber Company, but by 1924 the mill was closed permanently. The Leftwich Timber Company survived until 1944, when it consolidated with Tye River Timber Company into a company known as Tywich Corporation. The Tywich Corporation existed until June 2, 1959.
Because of the chestnut blight and the intervention of World War I, the railroad never reached its full business potential by hauling milled timber to the main line of the Southern Railway. The Virginia Blue Ridge Railway was much more successful hauling freight for Southern Mineral Products Corporation, a subsidiary of Vanadium Corporation of America. This company established a mine, mill, and chemical plant in 1930 at Piney River to manufacture titanium dioxide pigment, a substitute for white lead in making paint.
The Dominion Mineral Division of the Riverton Lime and Stone Company in 1939 and the International Mineral and Chemical Company in 1941, both built plants to mine and mill the Nelson County aplite deposits. Aplite is a primary ingredient in the manufacture of glass and rock-wool insulation. The Piney River area in Nelson County is the only important source of aplite rock known to exist in the United States. Other minerals and commodities carried by the railway during its career include feldspar, ilmenite ore, calcium phosphate, ferrous sulphate, fertilizer, coal, sulphur, kaolin clays, cooperage stock, acid, apples, and pulp wood. For more information about the history of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway and the timber companies, see Sentimental Journey by Carl M. Lathrop (1979) filed in Cubic 21 and copy in Rare Books.
Organization
These papers are arranged in six series: I) Correspondence of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway (Cubics 1-5); II) Correspondence with the Officers of the Company and their Chief Business Associates (Cubics 6-12); III) Topical and Subject Files (Cubics 13-26); IV) Financial and Administrative Records (Cubics 26-41); V) Unfoldered Bills of Lading; Delivery Receipts; and Telegrams (Cubics 42-48); and VI) Bound Volumes and Oversize Materials (Cubics 49-52 and various oversize locations).
Contents List
- Correspondence of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1914-1946, n.d. (Carton 1-5)
  - Correspondence of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1914-1946, n.d. (Carton 1-5)
- Correspondence with the Officers of the Company and their Chief Business Associates 1914-1956 (Carton 6-12)
  - Correspondence of James R. Caskie 1929-1956, 3 folders (Carton 6)
  - Correspondence of Edward Cobb 1953-1954 (Carton 6)
  - Correspondence of Fordyce Cobb 1915-1928, 7 folders (Carton 6)
  - Correspondence of Howard Cobb 1915-1949, 78 folders (Carton 6-9)
  - Correspondence of Kenneth Cobb 1947-1956 (Carton 9)
  - Correspondence of T.A. Fry, Vice-President 1950-1956, 4 folders (Carton 9)
  - Correspondence of J.H. Jester, Traffic Manager 1939-1956, 4 folders (Carton 9)
  - Correspondence of Charles F. Johnson 1922-1925, 4 folders (Carton 9)
  - Correspondence of Frank O. Lathrop, Superintendent 1915-1921, 20 folders (Carton 9-10)
  - Correspondence of E.H. McKenzie, Agent Southern Railway System 1935-1954 (Carton 10)
  - Correspondence of John W. Powell 1934-1945 January, 40 folders (Carton 10-12)
  - Correspondence of Morris E. Priesch, Haines Lumber Company 1918-1925, 8 folders (Carton 12)
  - Correspondence of Wilmer H. Righter (1873-1947), General Manager 1935-1949, 12 folders (Carton 12)
- Topical & Subject Files 1899-1979, n.d. (Carton 13-26)
  - A Miscellaneous ca. 1920, 1934-1943 (Carton 13)
  - Abrahams & Whitaker 1935-1936 (Carton 13)
  - Advertisements for Positions in the Virginia Blue Ridge Railroad 1946-1948 (Carton 13)
  - Advertising 1939-1949 (Carton 13)
  - A.J. White & Son 1915-1930, 2 folders (Carton 13)
  - A.N. Campbell & Company, Lynchburg, Va. 1934-1943 (Carton 13)
  - Agriculture, U.S. Department of 1940-1944 (Carton 13)
  - American Automatic Electric Sales Company, Richmond, Va. Office 1936-1941 (Carton 13)
  - American Short Line Railroad Association 1931-1953, 12 folders (Carton 13)
  - Analyses--Joseph Fahey 1936-1954 (Carton 13)
  - Analyses-General 1939-1947 (Carton 13)
  - Anchor Hocking Glass Corporation 1936-1943 (Carton 13)
  - Aplite Application for Commodity Rate to Southern Points 1939-1946 (Carton 13)
  - Aplite Application for Commondity Rate to Western Points--Carrier Proposal 1939-1940, 1951 (Carton 13)
  - Aplite Application for Commodity Rate to Western Points--Shipper's Proposal 1939-1940, 2 folders (Carton 13)
  - Aplite--Rate Matters & Divisions 1937-1951, 2 folders (Carton 14)
  - Aplite vs Slag--Competitive Rates 1945-1949 (Carton 14)
  - Aplite Waste or Fines (Scraplite)--Rates & Divisions 1939-1942 (Carton 14)
  - Apples & National Fruit Product Company 1944-1947 (Carton 14)
  - Applications 1940-1943 (Carton 14)
  - Articles of Association and By-Laws 1914 (Carton 14)
  - Association of American Railroads 1935-1943, A21-18B (Carton 14)
  - B Miscellaneous 1934-1943 (Carton 14)
  - Barker-Jennings Hardware Corporation 1935-1944 (Carton 14)
  - Basic Dolomite, Inc. re Koalin & Aplite 1937-1942 (Carton 14)
  - Bath National Bank 1920-1925 (Carton 14)
  - Batopilas Mining Company 1914-1936 (Carton 14)
  - Bee Tree Lumber Company 1916-1924, 4 folders (Carton 14)
  - Bee Tree Lumber Company--Financial Statements & Reports 1917-1923, 2 folders (Carton 14)
  - Black Hills Tin Company--Spodumene 1940-1943 (Carton 14)
  - British Honduras Timber & Railways 1922-1927 (Carton 14)
  - Bureau of Mines and Clay Deposit Report 1937-1956 (Carton 14)
  - C Miscellaneous 1934-1944 (Carton 14)
  - Calco Chemical Division, American Cyanamid Company 1944-1956 (Carton 14)
  - Car Hire--Per Diem, etc. 1935-1949 (Carton 14)
  - Clay--Rejection File 1939-1947 (Carton 14)
  - Climax Manufacturing Company Contract 1915 (Carton 14)
  - Coal Sales 1935-1940 (Carton 14)
  - Fordyce A. Cobb--Estate 1944-1952 (Carton 14)
  - J.A. Coffey--Property, etc. 1929-1955 (Carton 14)
  - O.V. Coffey--Account 1937-1943 (Carton 14)
  - Commendatory & Congratulatory Letters 1939-1952 (Carton 14)
  - Consolidated Feldspar Corporation & Carolina Mineral Company 1940-1949 (Carton 14)
  - Copperas (Ferrous Sulphanate)--Interstate Rate 1940-1941, 1954-1955 (Carton 14)
  - Copperas (Ferrous Sulphanate)--Intrastate Rate 1940, 1955 (Carton 14)
  - D Miscellaneous 1935-1944 (Carton 14)
  - Deaths 1940 (Carton 14)
  - The De Priest Bank 1929-1930 (Carton 14)
  - "Directory" of Rates & Addresses Prepared for John W. Powell 1942 (Carton 14)
  - Dominion Minerals, Inc. 1938-1956, 5 folders (Carton 14-15)
  - Dominion Minerals, Inc.--Claims 1939-1941 (Carton 15)
  - Dominion Minerals, Inc.--Covered Hopper Cars 1950-1953 (Carton 15)
  - Dominions Minerals Inc--Switch 1938-1947 (Carton 15)
  - E Miscellaneous 1930-1943 (Carton 15)
  - Employment 1940-1956 (Carton 15)
  - Equipment 1938-1956, 3 folders (Carton 15)
  - Equipment--Abandonments 1939-1940 (Carton 15)
  - Equipment--Cars, Railway & Motor 1940-1946 (Carton 15)
  - Equipment--Dominion Minerals 1939-1940 (Carton 15)
  - Equipment--Locomotives & Locomotive Units 1939-1946 (Carton 15)
  - Equipment--Rails 1939-1941 (Carton 15)
  - Equipment--Scales 1944-1946 (Folder 15)
  - Equipment--Scrap Material 1940-1949 (Carton 15)
  - Equipment--Steam Shovel 1939-1940 (Carton 15)
  - Expense Account--B.H. Smith 1940 (Carton 15)
  - Expense Account--Washington Office 1940-1956 (Carton 15)
  - Exploration Account 1942 (Carton 15)
  - F Miscellaneous 1935-1942 (Carton 15)
  - Farm Bills 1943-1944 (Carton 15)
  - Farmco Package Corporation, Norfolk, Virginia 1930-1938 (Carton 15)
  - Frank C. Farrell, Auditor with the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway, Leftwich Timber Company, & Tye River Timber Company 1916-1919 (Carton 15)
  - J.W. Fauber--Timber Land, Amherst County, Va. 1914 (Carton 15)
  - Feldspar and Nepheline Syenite 1939-1950 (Carton 15)
  - Ferebee Johnson Company, Lynchburg, Va. 1943-1944 (Carton 15)
  - Fire Damage Caused by the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1941-1943 (Carton 15)
  - First National Bank, Lovingston, Va. 1935-1944 (Carton 15)
  - First National Bank, Owego, New York 1915-1921 (Carton 15)
  - Fisher Products Corporation 1941-1943 (Carton 15)
  - Franklin Gold Mine, Fauquier County, Va. 1931-1937 (Carton 15)
  - G Miscellaneous 1934-1944 (Carton 15)
  - Mrs. O.L. Gannaway & Everett Whitehead 1950-1951 (Carton 15)
  - Garden Project 1943 (Carton 16)
  - General Chemical Company 1942-1948 (Carton 16)
  - George P. Fitchett & Son--Finance Contract & Deeds of Trust 1916 (Carton 16)
  - Georgia & Florida Railroad, H.W. Purvis, Receiver 1935-1937 (Carton 16)
  - Georgia Company 1929-1936, 3 folders (Carton 16)
  - Gillis & Pawel Magnesia Development, Webster, North Carolina 1940 (Carton 16)
  - The Glidden Company 1931-1948 (Carton 16)
  - Government Loan Correspondence 1920-1943, 3 folders (Carton 16)
  - Government Matters--Army Camp at Piney River & Lowesville 1943 (Carton 16)
  - Great Western Land Company, Polson, Montana 1921-1924 (Carton 16)
  - H Miscellaneous 1934-1944 (Carton 16)
  - H.K. Porter Company--Specification for Locomotive "Mogul" 1916 November 17 (Carton 16)
  - Dr. Frank L. Hess, Bureau of the Mines 1936-1942 (Carton 16)
  - Hire Freight Cars 1925-1933 (Carton 16)
  - Hope Falls Timper Corporation 1918-1938, 4 folders (Carton 16)
  - Hughes Tie & Lumber Company--Lawsuit 1922 (Carton 16)
  - I Miscellaneous 1935-1944 (Carton 16)
  - Ilmenite Ore 1920-1939 (Carton 16)
  - Imnemite Ore--Rate Matters & Divisions 1940-1944 (Carton 16)
  - Ilmenite Ore--Rates to Suspension Bridge, New York & Bridgeville, PA 1940-1944 (Carton 16)
  - Industrial Development 1935-1947, 2 folders (Carton 16)
  - Information Sources 1940-1943 (Carton 16)
  - Insurance Policy Rates 1953 (Carton 16)
  - International Minerals & Chemical Corporation 1956 (Carton 16)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission 1915-1954, 5 folders (Carton 16-17)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission--Application for Authority to Issue Securities and Notes 1920-1921 (Carton 17)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission--Application for a Loan by the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1920-1926, 3 folders (Carton 17)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission--Divisions of Joint Class Rates in Official Territory 1926-1934 (Carton 17)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission--Hours of Service Reports 1933-1940, 2 folders (Carton 17)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission--Locomotive Inspections 1923-1935 (Carton 17)
  - Ithaca Trust Company--Petitions from the Leftwich Timber Company & Discharge of Mortgate 1916-1924, 3 folders (Carton 17)
  - J-K Miscellaneous 1929-1943 (Carton 17)
  - J.P. Bell Company, Lychburg, Va. 1935-1944 (Carton 17)
  - J.W. Powell Company 1920-1938 (Carton 17)
  - John McCall Coal Company 1935-1938 (Carton 17)
  - Joint Facility with the Southern Railway Company Account 1933-1944 (Carton 17)
  - Kaolin File 1927-1947 (Carton 17)
  - V.V. Kelsey re the Virginia Feldspar Deposit 1931-1954, 10 folders (Carton 17-18)
  - L Miscellaneous 1932-1944 (Carton 18)
  - Lands Owned by the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1917 (Carton 18)
  - Leases--Conrad P. Campbell & Bartley W. Thompson Properties 1939, 1954-1956 (Carton 18)
  - Leases--G.H. Parr, T.W. Saunders, & Nathaniel Kidd Properties 1947-1956 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company 1916-1946, 4 folders (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Agreements & Contracts with A.J. & J.C. White 1914-1917 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Certificate of Incorporation & Statement 1912-1916 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Collateral Promissory Notes 1914-1934 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Contracts 1925-1944 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Contracts & Agreements with the Woodson Lumber company, Inc. 1917-1922 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Deeds 1914-1919 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Financial Statements 1914-1944, 2 folders (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--George P. Fitchetts & Son Notes 1915-1927 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Lands of Henry T. Cash & G.J. Cash 1914-1915 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Mortgages 1922 (Folder 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Sale of Property 1921, 1924-1925, 2 folders (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Taxes 1914-1944, 5 folders (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company--Tax Receipts from Amherst County, Va. 1916-1931 (Carton 18)
  - Leftwich Timber Company & Tye River Lumber Company--Tax Receipts from Nelso County, Va. 1919-1931 (Carton 18)
  - Legislation 1939-1950 (Carton 19)
  - Lowesville, Va. Station--Statement of Freight Business 1930-1931 (Carton 19)
  - Luck Constructionn Company, Contractor, Roanoke, Va. 1915-1916 (Carton 19)
  - M Miscellaneoous 1935-1943 (Carton 19)
  - M.K. Frank Iron and Steel Products, New York 1936-1937 (Carton 19)
  - M.J. Parr, Piney River, Va. 1936-1944, 3 folders (Carton 19)
  - Mc Miscellaneous 1939-1944 (Carton 19)
  - Maps--Florida 1932 (Carton 19)
  - Maps--Georgia 1932 (Carton 19)
  - Maps--Honduras 1899 (Carton 19)
  - Maps--North Carolina 1926 (Carton 19)
  - Maps--Virginia, especially Properties surroinding the Birginia Blue Ridge Railway and the Leftwich Timber Company 1917-1942, n.d. (Carton 19)
  - Maps--West Virginia 1932 (Carton 19)
  - Maps--Western Land Syndicate Estate Plan 1915 (Carton 19)
  - Martin Estate--Agreement 1933-1942 (Carton 19)
  - Maryland Car Wheel Company 1931-1933 (Carton 19)
  - George W. Mason--Property 1940-1952 (Carton 19)
  - W.E. Massie 1938-1943 (Carton 19)
  - Mawyer and Evans 1930 (Carton 19)
  - Meetings 1944-1956 (Carton 19)
  - Memorabilia 1917-1921, n.d. (Carton 19)
  - William Meredith, President of Titanium Alloy Manufacturing Company 1936-1943 (Carton 19)
  - Midwest Steel Corporation 1940-1944 (Carton 19)
  - G. Kibby Munson, Attorney 1942-1956 (Carton 19)
  - N Miscellaneous 1936-1944 (Carton 19)
  - National Lead Company 1920-1955 (Carton 19)
  - N.B. Handy Company, Lynchburg, Va. 1936-1937 (Carton 19)
  - Nelsonite Ore 1948-1949 (Carton 19)
  - Nepheline Syenite--Treasury Decisions 1940-1942 (Carton 19)
  - New York & Pennsylvania Railway Company--Appeal 1921 April 18 (Carton 19)
  - Norfolk & Western Railway 1935-1941 (Carton 19)
  - O Miscellaneous 1935-1944 (Carton 19)
  - Office of Defense Transportation 1938-1943 (Carton 19)
  - Office Memoranda 1941-1952 (Carton 19)
  - Official Classification Committee 1929-1932 (Carton 19)
  - Ordnance--Final Report 1918-1919, 2 folders (Carton 20)
  - Ordnance--Miscellaneous 1918-1919 (Carton 20)
  - P Miscellaneous 1915, 1932-1943 (Carton 20)
  - Passenger Car Repairs 1925-1931 (Carton 20)
  - Pay Roll 1943-1956 (Carton 20)
  - Pennsylvania Railroad Company 1930-1947 (Carton 20)
  - Piney River Kaolin District, Nelson County, Va. 1942-1948 (Carton 20)
  - Pitch-Pine Chemicals, Inc.--Agreement with John L. Weaver 1928-1929 (Carton 20)
  - Potomac Zinc Mining Company 1916-1925 (Carton 20)
  - John W. Powell--Power of Attorney, Mortgages & Deeds 1922-1925 (Carton 20)
  - Judge John W. Price 1937-1939 (Carton 20)
  - Properties--Ore Deposits, Mines, Options & Timber 1928-1956, n.d. (Carton 20)
  - Pulpwood Rates 1940-1944 (Carton 20)
  - Q-R Miscellaneous 1935-1944 (Carton 20)
  - Railroad Hobbyists & Data 1944-1947 (Carton 20)
  - Railroad Pass Requests 1920-1956, 9 folders (Carton 20)
  - Railroad Pass Requests--Curtailment 1941-1943 (Carton 20)
  - Republican National Committee 1940 (Carton 20)
  - Reservations 1940-1950 (Carton 20)
  - Rutile 1939-1943 (Carton 20)
  - S Miscellaneous 1934-1944 (Carton 21)
  - L.M. Saxton, General Manager 1937 (Carton 21)
  - Sentimental Journey by Carl M. Lathrop--History of the V.B.R.R. 1979 (Carton 21)
  - Sganzini Gold Mine Property, near Taos, New Mexico 1931 (Carton 21)
  - S.E. Shelton Option--Proposed Railroad Expansion 1934, 1947 (Carton 21)
  - Sherwin-Williams Company 1938-1951 (Carton 21)
  - Harold E. Simpson 1949-1956 (Carton 21)
  - Slag Rates 1944-1950, 2 folders (Carton 21)
  - Barney H. Smith 1940-1944 (Carton 21)
  - South Georgia Railway Company, J.W. Oglesby, Vice President 1937 (Carton 21)
  - South River Lumber Company 1925-1926 (Folder 21)
  - Southeastern Demurrage & Storage Bureau 1930-1939 (Carton 21)
  - Southeastern Demurrage & Storage Bureau--Bills 1925-1940, 6 folders (Carton 21)
    A21-19A
  - Southern Mineral Products Corporation 1931-1947, 3 folders (Carton 21)
  - Southern Railways System 1927-1955, 9 folders (Carton 21)
  - Southern Railway System--Docket #15879 Class Rates 1933-1934 (Carton 22)
  - Southern Railway System--Per Diem Relief 1933-1935 (Carton 22)
  - Southern Retort Company--Wood Distillation ca. 1927 (Carton 22)
  - Southern Short Line Railroad Conference Meetings 1940-1954, 2 folders (Carton 22)
  - Statso Milling Company, Charles T. Kett 1946-1948 (Carton 22)
  - State Corporation Commission 1915-1952, 4 folders (Carton 22)
  - State Corporation Commission--R.T. Wilson 1919-1920 (Carton 22)
  - Statistics 1939-1947 (Carton 22)
  - Statistics--Importations of Ilmenite Ore 1939-1943 (Carton 22)
  - Stocks & Bonds of the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1936-1956 (Carton 22)
  - Stone & Webster Engineering Corporation 1931-1933 (Carton 22)
  - Swift & Company re Koalin & Aplite 1947 (Carton 22)
  - Subscriptions & Orders 1921, 1939-1946 (Carton 22)
  - Sulphur Rates & Orders 1939-1949 (Carton 22)
  - Sulphuric Acid Rates & Divisions 1940-1944 (Carton 22)
  - T Miscellaneous 1935-1944 (Carton 22)
  - Tariffs, Division Sheets & Routing Assignments 1931-1948 (Carton 22)
  - Tariffs, Local--Rate Matters & Divisions 1936-1952, 2 folders (Carton 22)
  - Taxes 1935-1946 (Carton 22)
  - Taxes--Victory Tax Law 1943 (Carton 22)
  - Telephone & Telegraph--Miscellaneous 1938-1947 (Carton 22)
  - D.W. Thomas, General Manager, Chesapeake Western Railway 1934-1938 (Carton 22)
  - Tidewater Lumber Company 1921-1927, 13 folders (Carton 22-23)
  - Tidewater Lumber Company--Bills & Vouchers 1923-1924 (Carton 23)
  - Tidewater Lumber Company (5 folders) 1923-1924 (Carton 23)
  - Tidewater Lumber Company--Stock Certificates 1925 (Carton 23)
  - Tildesley Coal Company 1936-1944, 2 folders (Carton 23)
  - Tye River Steel Bridge & Turntable 1924 (Carton 23)
  - Tye River Steel Bridge built for the Virginia Blue Ridge Railway 1943 (Carton 23)
  - Tye River Timber Company 1915-1950, n.d., 5 folders (Carton 23)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Bee Tree Lumber Company Agreement 1916, 1924 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Bond Payment File 1922-1923 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Contract with Marquette-Kerr Lumber Company 1914 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Deeds of Trust and Articles of Incorporation 1913-1916 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Deeds 1914-1944 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Financial Statements 1914-1943, 2 folders (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Financial Statements, Minute & Stockholder Records 1918-1944 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Fire Insurance Policy 1922-1925 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Forest Industries Questionnaire & Schedule, Bureau of Internal Revenue 1919-1920 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Mortgage 1914 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Promissory Notes 1916-1928 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company--Taxes 1915-1944, 4 folders (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company and Leftwich Timber Company Consolidation 1941-1945, 2 folders (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company and Leftwich Timber Company Consolidation--Timber Tracts 1933-1943 (Carton 24)
  - Tye River Timber Company and Leftwich Timber Company Consolidation--Timber Tracts Acquisition by Federal Government for Forestry Reserve 1938-1943 (Carton 24)
  - Tywich Corporation 1924-1956 (Carton 24)
  - U-V Miscellaneous 1935-1944 (Carton 24)
  - U.S. James Engineering Corporation 1938-1948 (Carton 24)
  - Unemployment Compensation Commission of Virginia 1937-1938 (Carton 24)
  - Union Organization 1946-1956 (Carton 24)